hey guys Pastor mys here and I just want
to take a minute to invite you to check
out this powerful message on the fear of
God and what it really means uh listen
to it carefully it's going to change
your view of who God is especially as it
relates to his end time message for his
people so watch and be blessed
[Music]
the message today is
entitled the
2023 message
fear
God fear God and
it's it's not a statement it's a
question why is this message entitled
the 2023 message well uh in the year
1888 a very special message had been
preached by two men um by the name of at
Jones and EJ Wagner
and
these men preached a message that came
to be understood as the righteousness by
faith
message that was 1888 we are now in the
year
2023 and we're going to be speaking
about this
message and how it relates to God's
people particularly
at the end of
time so let us go to the screen and
we're going to
begin with Genesis chapter
32 Genesis chapter 32 beginning with
verse
one the Bible says here and Jacob went
on his way and the angels of God met him
and when Jacob saw them he said this is
God's host and he called the name of
that place
Maham and Jacob sent Messengers before
him to Esau his brother onto the land of
sier the country of Edom and he
commanded them saying thus shall ye
speak unto my Lord Esau thy servant
Jacob saith thus I have sojourned with
laben and stayed there until now and I
have oxen and asses flocks and men's
servant and women's servants and I have
sent to tell my Lord that I might find
Grace in thy
sight and The Messengers returned to
Jacob saying we came to thy brother Esau
and also he cometh to meet thee and
400 men with
him verse 7 then Jacob was greatly
afraid and distressed and he divided the
people that was with him and the flocks
and herds and came into two bands and
then we're going to jump down to verse
24 and Jacob was left alone and there
Wrestled a man with him until the break
of day come back with me for a
moment and let's break this story down
you'll remember that years
earlier Jacob had stolen the birthright
from his twin brother Esau
and after this event he fled for his
life because his brother wanted to kill
him and so he is away from home for 20
years when the Lord tells him that it is
time for him to return Jacob has since
repented he is married he has two wives
and children and his his flock is
beginning to grow
and Genesis 32 picks up where Jacob
realizes that he is about to meet with
his brother Esau whom he has not
seen since that deceptive act 20 years
earlier and so he sends before him these
presents and Gifts in an attempt to
appease
Esau but when his servants return
they say to him Esau is coming to meet
you not
alone he's coming to meet you with
men now you all help me out and you tell
me what do you think Esau I'm sorry what
do you think Jacob is
feeling as he hears that Esau is coming
with
400 men what are your
thoughts is Esau coming to
talk what is he coming to
do you are probably
thinking they are
coming Esau is
coming to
destroy Jacob and his entire
family it's Revenge time
the Bible tells us that Jacob was
greatly afraid and then the Bible says
that this
being appears in the night and begins
wrestling with Jacob now you can imagine
that Jacob as he does not know who this
being is that he is wrestling with must
be
afraid thinking this is
Esau this is
it I am in
trouble let's go back to the
screen the Bible tells us in Jeremiah
30: 7 that a time is coming that is
known as Jacob's time of trouble the
Bible
says alas for that day is great so that
none is like it it is even the time of
Jacob's trouble but he shall be saved
out of it the Bible lets us know that
there is coming a Time
where there will be a time of trouble
like none that has ever existed before
and Daniel 12 mentions this time as that
time period Daniel 12 ver1 but but I
want you to note here that that the time
is described as Jacob's time of trouble
because just as Jacob went through a
very stressful period a very stressful
situation here fighting in for his life
so this is going to be repeated at the
very end of
time we know that Jacob was terrified it
was mental anguish a and that becomes
very significant because when we look at
the message that is to go into the world
at the very end of time going into all
the world in Revelation
14:6 the Bible says here and I saw
another Angel flying in the midst of
Heaven having the Everlasting gospel to
preach unto them that dwell on the earth
and to Every Nation Kindred tongue and
people saying with a loud voice
fear God and give glory to him for the
hour of his judgment is come and worship
him that made Heaven and Earth the sea
and The Fountains of water
now beloved I need you to understand
here and let's let's let's think about
this this message is a call for the
world to fear
God now even when unbelievers hear this
when people who don't believe in the
Bible hear this they're saying in their
minds what kind of message is this from
a god of love that is calling men to be
afraid to fear
fear
Him Now I know what you're thinking
right well well the word fear uh uh it
means it really means reverence and so
God is just saying to reverence but I
want you to check this out we're going
to go back to the screen this is the
Greek word that is used for that word
fear here it is on the
screen for and it means to
frighten that is to be alarmed by
analogy to be in awe of that is revered
be sore afraid to fear exceedingly to
reverence
now I know we we can go with the with
the reverence but the word also means to
be
afraid to be sore
afraid anybody have any
phobias put a one in the chat if you
have a
phobia the question becomes why is God
why is this message
going to the whole
world calling the world to be
afraid to be
frightened to be to to to fear
God what is God doing
here well we might ask the question why
is God
saying to fear Him what what is there to
be afraid of and it tells us in the text
it says why why should we fear God for
notice the screen
for the hour of his judgment is
come
yeah that's why we need to be
afraid the hour of his judgment is come
and that causes fear it really really
does why because Ecclesiastes 12:14 says
this God shall bring every work into to
judgment with every secret thing whether
it be good or whether it be evil and yet
we ought to fear why because just look
at Isaiah's response when he comes face
to face with God in the year that King
oziah died I saw also the Lord sitting
upon a throne high and lifted up and his
train filled the
temple above it stood the seraphim and
each one had six wings with Twain he
covered his face and with Twain he did
cover his feet and with Twain he did fly
and one Cried unto another and said holy
holy holy the Lord of hosts the whole
earth is full of his glory and the post
of the door moved at the voice of him
that cried and the house was filled with
smoke now watch this watch Isaiah's
response who says then said I woe is me
for I am undone because I'm a man of
unclean lips and I dwell in the midst of
a people of unclean lips for my eyes
have seen the king the Lord of hosts so
do y'all
understand what there is why this
message elicits
fear be afraid why because we are undone
why because we are unclean and we dwell
in the midst of an unclean people people
when we understand the the Holiness of
God and we look at ourselves yes there
is
reason to
fear there is reason to fear God why
because he now holds Our Fate In His
Hands So this message is for the whole
world
fear God why because the judgement is
come and he is the one that holds your
faith in his hand now here's the thing
y'all why is God calling us to fear
Him let me tell you why are y'all ready
for this listen to what the Bible says
in Psalm 33 and verse
18 Psalm
33:18 behold the eyes of the Lord is
upon the eye of the Lord is upon them
that fear Him upon them that hope in his
Mercy all
right God
says those who fear me those who
understand the importance of of this
judgment those who understand that I
hold their fate in their hands those who
fear God those the eye of the Lord is
upon them that fear him that hope in his
mercy so to fear God is in set in
essence to hope for his Mercy let's go
back to the screen for as the heavens
are higher than the earth so great is
his
Mercy is his Mercy toward them that fear
him Psalm 103 verse 11:2 as far as the
East is from the West so far has he
removed our transgressions from us like
as a father pth his son or his children
so the Lord pith them that fear Him He
knoweth our frame he
rememberthe are dust as for man his days
are as grass and as a flower F the
flower of the field so he flourisheth
for the wind passeth over it and is gone
and the place thereof shall know no more
watch this verse
17 but the mercy of the Lord is from
Everlasting to Everlasting upon them
that fear him and his righteousness unto
the children's childrens to such as keep
his Covenant and to those that remember
his Commandments to do them do you'all
understand what's going on
here God is calling the entire world to
fear him so that he can extend
Mercy to
them come on y'all listen listen let's
keep following this train of thought
Psalm
18 Psalm 18 uh verse 4 says let them now
that fear the lord say that his mercy
endureth forever Psalm 14711 the lord
taketh pleasure in them that fear Him in
those that hope in his Mercy Luke 1:50
and his Mercy is on them that fear Him
from generation to generation in other
words beloved God desires to extend
Mercy to them that fear Him the fear of
the Lord is an acknowledgment that we
have sinned against his law and against
him and that we deserve punishment but
the reward of that
fear listen to me the reward word of
that fear is
Mercy it is
Mercy now hold that thought right there
because this is the first Angel's
message that we just read fear God and
give glory to him but now I need to jump
down to the third Angel's message please
follow with me for Godly sorrow worketh
repentance to Salvation not to be
repented of but the sorrow of the world
worketh death you see that
fear fear of God leads to a Godly sorrow
that works repentance that comes in
connection with the mercy of God so hold
that thought we're going to go to the
third Angel's message in Revelation 14
Revelation
14:9 and the third Angel followed them
saying with a loud voice if any man
worship the beast in His image and
receive his Mark in his forehead or in
his hand the same shall drink of the
wine of the wrath of God which is poured
out without mixture into the cup of his
indignation and he shall be tormented
with fire and brimstone in the presence
of the Holy Angels and in the presence
of the lamb and the smoke of their
torment ascendeth up forever and ever
they have no rest they or night who
worship the beast in His image and whoso
receiveth the mark of his name now watch
the next verse y'all because we read
this third Angel's message it's a
warning against receiving the mark of
the beast but we often leave out this
last part of the third Angel's message
which is by far the most crucial part of
the third Angel's message because here
it says here's the patience of the
Saints here are they that keep the
Commandments of God and have the faith
of Jesus okay so come back with me and
we understand what the Commandments of
God are right they are the Ten
Commandments and and God's end time
people are going to be found keeping
those Commandments but there is
something also called the faith of Jesus
now next week I'm going to be preaching
a message called the faith of Jesus what
exactly is it and why do we need it now
I'm going to get into a little bit of it
here today but I need you to just be
aware of that that next week I'm going
to be dealing strictly with the faith of
Jesus so hold you just put the on the
shelf for a moment and let's come back
we're going to look at the faith of
Jesus now but from another perspective
okay one that I won't talk about next
week but I'm talking about today so what
is this faith of Jesus that is so
necessary particularly in this in this
end time message and in this time of
Jacob's trouble like we're talking about
right this time where God's people are
going to be going through some kind of
Anguish that's going to require them to
a keep the Commandments of God and be
have the faith of Jesus listen to
this in the book of Galatians chap 2: 16
the Bible says
this knowing that a
man is not justified by The Works of the
law but by the faith of Jesus Christ
even we have believed in Jesus Christ
that we might be
justified by the Faith of Christ Christ
and not by the words of the law for by
the words of the law shall no flesh be
justified so check this out you guys why
do we need the faith of
Jesus the faith of Jesus Christ is what
justifies
us okay okay okay
okay let's go back to the screen let me
read that again knowing this knowing
that a man is not justified by The Works
of the law but by the faith of Jesus
Christ so the faith of Jesus Christ is
necessary because it is what
justifies us now why is
justification so important in the
context of the Three Angels
messages yes you got it because the
first Angel's message is about judgment
and in any judgment that I'm facing I
would rather be
justified than
condemned put a one in the chat if y'all
understand what I just
said if you're in a judgment there's
only one of two outcomes for you you
will either be justified or you will be
condemned so what the Bible is telling
us
is that those who keep the Commandments
of God and have the faith of Jesus are
the ones that end up being
justified in the
Judgment but that entire justification
process is only given them because of
God's
mercy all right are y'all with me so far
we are
justified by the faith of Jesus Christ
so when the Bible says here are they
that keep the Commandments of God and
have the faith of Jesus Christ it is
actually pointing to the faith of Jesus
Christ as the reason that we are
justified in the
Judgment wow okay I got way too excited
just now and my changer for my slides
just flew out my hands and I cannot
leave the screen to go get my slides so
I'm just going to go pull my computer
and I don't know if my people can
control this from this end um but if you
can that would be great why I need to
just calm
down I need to just calm down okay all
right so here's why this is significant
y'all that's good when I read the slide
you just change it to the next one and
when I'm ready to go to the screen we'll
do so yeah let's go back let's go back
and and and I want you to check this out
now
remember that as a church we received a
message in 1888 that we
call the righteousness by faith message
now I want you to note what Ellen White
has to say about this message and
particularly about the subject we're
talking about right now because check
this out she says in the review and
Herald April 1
1890 the Bible says here
many have been inquiring if the message
of justification by faith is the third
Angel's message and I have in and I have
answered it is the third Angel's message
in Verity let's keep reading the prophet
declares and after these things I saw
another angel fly another angel coming
down from heaven having great power and
the Earth was lightened with his glory
let's keep going brightness and glory
and power are to be connected with the
third Angel's message and conviction
will follow wherever it is preached in
demonstration of the spirit let's keep
reading how will any of our Brethren
know when this light shall come to the
people of God as yet we certainly have
not seen the light that answers to this
description
God has light for his people and all who
will accept it will see the sinfulness
of remaining in a lukewarm condition
they will heed the counsel of the true
witness and his and and when he says be
zealous therefore and repent behold I
stand at the door and knock If any man
hear my voice and open the door I will
come into him and will Su with him the
Bible tells us beloved that it is
justification by faith
that that redeems the people of God but
we're being told by the spirit of
Prophecy listen carefully that
justification by faith is the third
Angel's message in
Verity yes the third Angel's message in
Verity
meaning that this message of
justification by faith is the message
that is supposed to be going forth into
all the
world she says when this message is
received it's going to work a powerful
transformation so so again note with me
on the screen the Bible says in in
Romans chapter 5 and verse verse one
therefore being justified by faith we
have peace with God through our Lord
Jesus Christ all right
um listen
y'all hold
on when we are
justified by faith the text says we have
peace with
God let's read it again y'all therefore
being justified by faith we have peace
with God through our Lord Jesus Christ
verse Two by whom also we have access by
this faith into the grace word we stand
and rejoice in the hope of the glory now
why is this so significant let me tell
you why this is significant because
Jesus said Peace I leave with you my
peace I give unto you not as the world
giveth give I unto you let not your
heart be troubled neither let it be what
come on
y'all neither Let It Be
Afraid all right hold on y'all wait a
minute don't be
afraid don't be let's go to the next
slide let's go to the next Slide the
Bible says here there is no fear in love
but perfect love casteth out Fe fear
because watch this because fear has
torment he that fearth is not made
perfect in love all right y'all hold on
a
second the the the the the first Angel's
message says fear
God fear Go I mean come on think about
it think about it think about God from
heaven
fear
me do you understand that that when he
says fear me what he's doing is he's
trying to get you to understand just how
bad your situation
is and when you understand that there's
a judgment and that that you have
nothing where whereby you can stand
before God and now you're depending upon
his Mercy he says all right through my
Mercy I'm going to extend to
you
justification and and and when we are
Justified beloved we end up having peace
with God and when we have peace with God
we are not afraid of God in other words
beloved God is trying to get us to
understand that he is not a God that
wants us to be afraid of him he is a god
that is wanting us to have peace with
him
are y'all catching
this watch this watch this let's go back
to the screen let's go back to the
screen and the same word here for afraid
for fear there is no fear in love is the
word watch this fob
Phobos which means to be put in fear
alarm or fright to be afraid of
exceedingly Fair Terror it is literally
yall listen to me it is the same word or
or it is a a different version of the
same word that is used in Revelation
chapter
14 perfect love casts out fear meaning
God does not really want us to be afraid
of him what he's saying is I'm trying to
give you my
peace to cast out your phobia
then watch this if this is the case then
the Three Angels messages and the third
Angel's message in particular is
designed to move us from a place of fear
to a place of
Peace did you all catch
this the third Angel's message is
designed to move us from a place of
fearing God to a place of peace with
God and now watch how it makes sense
y'all watch how let's break this thing
down let's go back to the screen see
here's what I want you to understand
fear is the beginning of
wisdom according to Psalm 110 the fear
of the Lord is the beginning of which
wisdom a good understanding have all
they that do his Commandments his praise
endureth forever so watch this watch
this the beginning of wisdom is the fear
of
God so so the fear of God is the first
sign of wisdom for you H you're pretty
wise why because you you have come to
the place where you fear God but fearing
God that is only the beginning of wisdom
it's the starting point of
wisdom now now the fear of God
ultimately leads to righteousness it
leads to us doing what is right now
watch this if the fear of the Lord leads
to righteousness watch what the work of
righteousness is let's go back to the
screen and the work of
righteousness shall
be
peace and the effect of righteousness
quietness and Assurance forever in other
words y'all in other
words in other
words I know Samantha I know I know I
know and you know what it is so funny
that you say that because as I was
reading the spirit of Prophecy today she
was she was saying how there were some
who were in those days saying we cannot
preach justification by faith too much
because people will think that we are
antinomian we are against the law and
she was like no no no you got it all
wrong this is why she said that
justification by faith is the third
Angel's message in
Verity
wow wow so so watch this the fear of the
Lord is the beginning of wisdom and that
leads to the work of righteousness but
the end result of the work of
righteousness is peace
it is
peace wow fear begins the process peace
ends the
process so that whereas when we're first
introduced to God there is this fear wo
is me I'm undone I'm a man of unclean
lips I dwell in the midst of an unclean
people I'm unworthy that initial fear
which is the right response when you
come to God take off your shoes you're
standing on hold
ground you are unclean you cannot stand
in my presence without being consumed
that be that is the beginning of wisdom
because you
realize there is nothing I can do to
save
myself but beloved that fear God
designed God is going to use that fear
and turn it to
peace now I need you to check this out
because because
justification by faith the only way we
can be justified listen to me the only
way we can be justified is through that
fear because it is through that fear
that we realize we have done
wrong and then when we have done wrong
the Bible says that we must
repent fear God and give glory to him
for the hour of his judgment is come is
really a call to
repentance but I need y'all to
understand something I I need y'all to
understand something
here and this is a point beloved that
that many people have failed over I need
you to to follow this
carefully
you cannot
repent on your
own you cannot repent on your own
let let let me let me read
you the verse in Acts chapter 5 in Acts
chapter 5 verse 31 the Bible says him
speaking of Jesus has God exalted with
his right hand to be a prince and a
savior for to give repentance to Israel
and forgiveness of
sins here's what I need y'all to
understand everyone
repentance is a gift of
God you cannot repent on your own it is
God who gives that
gift the reason why that's so important
to understand beloved is because
repentance is in essence then by by
faith because we cannot do it on our own
so when we talk about righteousness by
faith RBF we usually miss the fact that
in order to attain that righteousness by
faith there must first be repentance by
faith
RBF repentance by faith why because we
cannot repent on our own our repentance
is as filthy rags our repentance is
saying hey I have the power in and of
myself to turn away from sin and you
don't this is why God gives it we must
listen to me y That's why we don't
repent before we come to Jesus we come
to Jesus and then he gives us the gift
of
repentance and the problem is that many
us took repentance into our own hands
and therefore have never really
experienced the gift of repentance given
by
Jesus let me let me demonstrate to
you um what I mean do you remember do
you remember um Pharaoh a guy by the
name of
pharaoh how Pharaoh would would would
you know he would get him he would God
told him you know let my My People Go
Pharaoh's like I'm not letting them go
and then God would bring a plague and
then Pharaoh would do what Pharaoh would
repent but the repentance wasn't genuine
because it wasn't coming from the
spirit so every time something happened
Moses pray for me that's what he was
saying Moses pray for me tell God to
take these things away and you know what
God would actually follow through hey
I'm I'm going to take this things and
and then pharah would right back to what
he was doing
before right back to what he was doing
before beloved what we need to
understand is that we need to be praying
for
repentance you don't just walk up into
God's house and take something that
doesn't belong to you hey I'm taking
repent you actually have to pray for it
Lord give me repentance because I cannot
repent on my own when I Repent it's a
joke
my repentance power is not worth a
lot so when I come to you Lord I'm sorry
forgive me again that's all my
repentance that's all me Lord except my
repentance here's God says no I'm the
you need to understand that every part
of your salvation belongs to me you
can't come to me without me you you
can't repent without me you can do
nothing
nothing without
me I'm going to read a quote and I don't
typically do this in my sermons but I
need to read this quote and it is a
littleit it is a little extensive but I
need you to listen listen carefully
y'all many have a nominal faith in
Christ but they know nothing of that
vital dependence upon him which
appropriates the merits of a crucified
and Risen Savior
of this nominal Faith now
remember remember y'all come back with
me for a moment Remember come back with
me for a moment remember there's the
faith of
Jesus and then she's talking about this
nominal Faith so there's a nominal faith
and then there's the faith of
Jesus so come on let's go back let's go
back she says of this nominal Faith
James says Thou believeth there is one
God and you do well the Devils also
believe and tremble but will you know o
vain man that faith without works is
dead watch this many concede that Jesus
Christ is the savior of the world but at
the same time they hold themselves away
from him and fail to repent of their
sins fail to accept of Jesus as their
personal savior their faith is simply
the ascent of the mind and judgment to
the truth but the truth is is not
brought into the heart that it might
sanctify the soul and transform the
character come back with me for a moment
y'all what we just read is that there
are many people who ascent and believe
the
truth they're like whoa wait a minute
The Three Angels messages whoa wait a
minute the Sabbath whoa yo wait a minute
wait a minute the Judgment wait a minute
diet wait a minute they
they mentally ascent and are even
baptized I
believe I
believe and yes they believe yes we
believe and yet we're told that this is
a nominal
Faith because the truth has not
penetrated the heart it doesn't mean oh
man I really love this message you can
love the message and the truth not
penetrate your
heart come on come on follow this follow
this for whom he did Forno he did also
predestinate to be conformed to the
image of his son that he might be the
firstborn among many Brethren moreover
whom he did predestin them he also
called and whom he called them he also
Justified and whom he justified them he
also glorified calling and justification
are not one of the same thing calling is
the drawing of The Sinner to Christ and
it is a work wrought by the Holy Spirit
upon the heart convicting of sin and
inviting to repentance now watch
this no man of himself can
repent and make himself worthy of the
blessing of
justification the Lord Jesus is
constantly seeking to impress the
sinner's mind and attract him to Behold
Him the the the Lamb of God which taketh
away the sins of the world we cannot
take a step towards spiritual life save
as Jesus draws and strengthens the soul
and leads us to experience that
repentance which needeth not be repented
of do y'all catch
this if you are tired of repenting and
repenting and repenting and repenting
try Jesus his
repentance try asking God try asking
Jesus can you give me that gift of
repentance cuz my repentance is man
they're just likeo they are horrible cuz
I really be meaning my repentance too I
really really be meaning it and then it
just turns out to be ropes of
sand Lord I cannot repent on my
own so I am pleading with you to give me
the gift
give me that gift of
repentance now beloved what happens when
this begins to happen we begin to get a
genuine picture of ourselves because now
we see I can't do anything
right I have no reason to boast I didn't
make the
decision like it it wasn't my repentance
the Lord drew me and I
responded he made the first step and I
responded the reason people are lost is
because they don't respond to the
invitation of Jesus they don't respond
hey I've got repentance I can give it to
you because you can't do it on your own
but I can give it to you if you would
like God is trying to call us beloved a
and watch
this it it is so amazing beloved let's
go back to this story remember the story
of Jacob how he's how he's in this
troublous period and he's wrestling why
because he's afraid of the man he's
wrestling
with and he finally realizes that this
man is God and now I want you to watch
this in Genesis 32:2 watch this y'all
Genesis 32:2 the Bible says here and
when he saw that he prevailed not
against him he touched the hollow of his
thigh and the hollow of Jacob's thigh
was out of joint and he he wrestled with
him and he said let me go for the day
breth yo listen to me I'mma finish
reading the
text God said let me
go let me ask you a
question when God says let me go how how
does that make you
feel how does that make make you feel
let me go get off of
me it's as if God is like Jacob I don't
care about you get off of me you're a
sinner you're vile you're ungodly you
look at all the things you've done in
your past get off of me get away from me
be afraid of me get off of me before get
off of me or else
beloved sometimes we go through these
experiences where we feel like God is
saying let go of
me let go of me get off of
me but I need you to understand that
when God said let go of me he didn't
really mean let go of me
When God says when the Bible says fear
God when God's saying fear me he you
understand he's saying that but he means
something
else let go of me Jacob give up why
don't you let
go when Jacob knew who he was wrestling
with let go of me meant hold on
Michelle y'all can't just let go of me
meant hold on let go of me meant don't
let go let go of me meant I love you and
I need you to understand that no matter
what it what see what you think may come
in between me and you I need you to be
so determined in your walk with me that
you will never let me go and beloved
this is what God is wanting from us
today he says I never want you to let
let me go Lord you want to be afraid of
you I want you to have peace with me
Lord you want me to let go of you and
give up because I'm unworthy no I want
you to never let
go don't give up don't let
go and so the text says he said let me
go for the day
breakthe go except thou bless me and
then he said unto him what is thy name
what is thy name and he said Jacob and
he said thy name shall be called No More
Jacob but Israel for as a prince thou
has power with God and with men and has
prevailed do y'all understand what this
what this time of trouble is
is what this time of trouble beloved
this this time where God is saying
there's going to be this this time of
Jacob's trouble God is saying I need you
to have faith that is so powerful faith
that is kind of like like the faith of
Jesus cuz you're going to need the faith
of I'm getting into my sermon for next
week so let me just stop let me just
stop um I need you to not let
go I need you to stay with
me I need you to not give up I need you
to throw yourself on my Mercy come on
let's go to the screen we're almost
there guys let's go to the screen Jacob
watch this jacob had received the
blessing for his soul which he longed
for his sin as a supplanter and deceiver
had been pardoned the crisis of his life
was passed doubt perplexity and remorse
had embittered his experience but now
all was changed and sweet was the piece
of reconciliation with God watch this
jacob no longer feared to meet his
brother God who had forgiven his sin
could could move the heart of Esau also
to accept the humil his humiliation and
repentance I need y'all to understand
beloved that Jacob went from a place of
fear to a place of
Peace did you catch that Jacob went from
a place of fear to a place of
peace and it is because beloved Jacob
repented
God had given Jacob that gift of
repentance and he repented and even
though he doubted even though he was
like man I'm not sure if this repentance
is genuine it was God that had given it
to him and he had to go through a
wrestling to really come to terms that
yes I have been forgiven but beloved I
need you to understand that the closer
we get to God the more we see nothing in
ourselves why God should accept us why
God God should receive us but he says
nonetheless let me go translated do not
let me
go the purpose of the Three Angels
messages beloved that that is to go into
a world that is suffering from Fear
right now fearing this and fearing that
and fearing that and fearing that and
fearing all these different things God
says Okay I want y'all to fear me fear
me because if you fear
me then I can be the source of your
healing I can bring you
peace in the midst of the
storm I can set you
free now now now now come on y we are
almost there we are almost there check
this out y'all check this out check this
out so so so let's go to the screen
let's go to the screen and and beloved
listen this is why
this is why uh
um in Revelation
3:18 the the Bible says this here the
Bible says God speaking to the leodan
church his end time people says
something absolutely significant he says
first of all he says to them that they
are
lukewarm that they are rich increased
with Goods knowing not that they are
miserable wretched naked and blind and
now watch this you guys he says the the
the the the key is this I counsel thee
to buy of me gold tried in the fire that
thou mayest be rich all right how many
of you would like to buy gold tried in
the fire that you may be
rich put a one in the chat if you think
man I need that gold so that I can be
rich the question is rich in
what rich in
what cuz we quote that verse all the
time we need to buy gold in the fire
that we may be rich but rich in
what okay okay Le let's find out rich in
what let's go to the book of Ephesians
chapter 2:4 where the Bible says but
God just note my quietness y'all just
note my
quietness what is God rich in
but God who is rich in
Mercy for his great love wherewith he
loved us even when we were dead in sins
has quickened us together with Christ
and then watch this by
grace are you saved and has raised us up
together and made us sit together in
Heavenly places in Christ Jesus that in
the ages to come he might show the
exceeding Riches of his grace and his
kindness toward us through Christ Jesus
for by grace are you saved through faith
and that not of yourself it is the gift
of God y'all catch this God says I'm
rich in Mercy so I need you to buy gold
of me to to to to to ask my
Mercy if you buy the gold you're going
to be rich in Mercy now I need you to
understand that the gold in the Bible is
symbolic of
Faith so God is saying that it is my
faith the faith of Jesus Christ I'm
trying to give you my faith so that I
may justify you so that you may be rich
by having received Mercy from
me why is he counseling us to do this if
we're already good why is he counseling
us to do this if we already got it
together we are the remant church we got
it down we keep the Commandments of God
what do you mean God by gold of
you we keep the Commandments remember
the remember Revelation 142 here are
they that keep the Commandments of God
oh yeah and have the faith of Jesus but
the Commandments of
God yeah yeah you know the faith but the
Commandments of God nobody else is doing
that we do that
we keep the Commandments of
God God says yeah you're rich you think
you're
rich and increased with goods and have
need of nothing what else does he tell
us to do watch this y'all he says and
white rment that thou mayest be clothed
and that the shame of thy nakedness do
not appear and anoint thine eyes with
isow that thou may see what is this
about here's the here is the a key point
Y I need y'all to catch this we're about
to bring this in Beloved we're about to
see something
absolutely terrifying and the same time
reassuring you see there is only one
other place in the Bible where nakedness
and eyes and reignment is mentioned
together it's only other one other place
where nakedness and eyes and and and and
and shame
are
mentioned in Genesis 3:7 the Bible says
and the eyes of them both Adam and Eve
were
opened and they knew that they were
naked and they sewed fig leaves together
and made themselves aprons now I want
y'all to catch this cuz you may not you
may not be catching this right
now listen to me what God is saying
is that at least Adam and Eve knew they
were
naked their eyes were
open they knew they were
naked y'all don't know that you're naked
y'all don't know that you're miserable
y'all don't know that you're wretched
y'all don't know that you're blind you
don't know you think you're
rich you think you got it you think that
that that that as the remnant Church
y'all y'all are good to go you think
that because you know about the Sabbath
you think that because you you
understand that the law of God doesn't
change you think that you think you got
it but you don't even know
that the repentance that you gave me was
your own
repentance that while you have faith in
the
message you don't have a heart faith in
me you don't even know that you're
miserable and wretched and naked and
blind Adam and Eve knew and that's why I
I could work with
them they knew they hid themselves
you're walking around here not even
realizing you're naked like man look at
me hey we got this we're good I'm
good God is saying we must see ourselves
for who we really are before we
understand truly understand the fear of
God
I need you to know to see who you really
are you see in the Book of Matthew
chapter 26 verse 31 Jesus said unto them
all you shall be offended because of me
this night for it is written I will
Smite the shepherd and the sheep of the
flock shall be scattered but after I am
risen again I will go before you into
Galilee but Peter answered and said unto
him I am rich and increased with Goods
I'm sorry I'm sorry Peter answered and
said unto him though all men shall be
offended because of thee yet will I
never be offended and yet Jesus says to
him Peter Jesus Peter you will deny me
three
times now when Peter sat without the
palace a damsel came came unto him
saying thou also with with Jesus of
Galilee but he denied before them all
saying I know not what you say and when
he was gone outto the porch another maid
saw him and said unto them that were
with that were there this fellow was
also with Jesus of Nazareth and again he
denied with a note saying I do not know
the man and after a while came unto him
they that stood by and said to Peter
surely Thou Art also one of them for thy
speech berth thee and then began he to
curse and to swear saying I know not the
man and immediately the crowed and
Peter remembered the words of Jesus
which said unto him before the Crow
Thou shalt deny me Thrice and he went
out and
wept
bitterly come on
y'all it was when Peter came face to
face with
death fa to face with a
crisis that he came to the Stark
realization I
believe him to be the Messiah I believe
this message
but Faith had not
penetrated his
heart he was miserable wretched naked
and blind and knew it
not and how many of us are in that same
situation
today Ellen White says
this it isn't a crisis
that character is revealed when the
earnest voice proclaimed at
midnight behold the bridegroom cometh go
you out to meet
him when that message was proclaimed and
the sleeping virgins were aroused from
their Slumber it was seen who had made
preparation for the
event both parties were taken
unawares but one was prepared for the
emergency and the other was found
without
preparation so now a sudden and unlooked
for Calamity something that brings the
soul face to face with death will show
whether there is any real faith in the
promises of
God it will show whether the soul is
sustained by Grace the great final test
comes at the close of human probation
when it will be too late for the Soul's
need to be supplied
brothers and sisters My
Friends
Church God is trying to wake us
up he's trying to wake us up with this
message that we are told is called
justification by faith not by your
works not by your repentance
everything is by faith repentance by
faith
justification by
righteousness by
faith it is all him and none of us in
fact we are
told that justification by
faith
is the humbling
of man in the
dust so that we realize that it is none
of us and all of
him beloved today I I appeal to
you before we get to that
place where we have that rude awakening
like
Peter in a time when it is too late may
we now go back to
God and if we need to go back to the
beginning and say Lord my repentance in
my whole Christian walk has been my
repentance it was never yours and so now
Lord I'm praying to you Lord this thing
that I struggle with and that thing and
that thing and that thing and that Lord
I'm asking you now give me the
repentance that need not be repented of
give me that
repentance give me that justification
it's not mine it's yours give me that
righteousness it's not mine it's yours
Lord please help me start from the
beginning and teach me show me what
repentance is and if that repentance
takes a minute to receive or a day to
receive or a week to receive or a month
to receive help me to keep praying for
that repentance until I get it because
I'm tired of manufacturing my own
repentance and which ultimately leads me
just to say I I I'm still afraid I still
fear I don't have the peace of God the
Three Angels messages beloved is
designed to lead us from Fear to peace
and Jesus says come unto me all ye that
labor and are heavy laden and I will
give you rest I will give you peace but
you have to come to me not on an
intellectual level it must be of the
heart and if it is your desire to day
you're saying today
Lord
please grant me the gift of
repentance I've been using my own
repentance week after week month after
month year after year Lord I am praying
now that you would grant me
repentance create that PR process in me
that I may have the
peace that you so desire for me to have
with
you if that's your desire beloved put
that one in the chat and while you
putting that one in the chat I'm going
to lift you in prayer I'm going to lift
us in prayer beloved because you know
what this message does this message lays
all of our glory in the
dust none of me and all of of Christ
heavenly
father thank you for speaking to
us thank you Lord for opening our eyes
because we have not seen we have not
even been able to see our
nakedness Lord please we're praying
today that you would grant us the gift
of
repentance the gift of
justification please Lord move upon us
and then Lord when when we have received
it may we go out and preach the Three
Angels
messages especially that third Angel's
message that we have been told will be
will be what lightens the Earth with its
Glory that we may go to people and say
listen God has a has a gift for you and
if you would but receive it you will
have peace with him
please Lord may this message lighten the
Earth with its
glory is our prayer in Jesus name amen
and amen
[Music]